Kurt Taylor, PhD

Epidemiologist / Health Data Scientist

Pristol, UK

% www.kurttaylor.io

in LinkedIn

GitHub

y Twitter

\$+447425608190

EXPERIENCE

Senior Research Associate in Medical Statistics and Health Data Science

Bristol Medical School, University of Bristol

February 2022 - Ongoing

Pristol, UK

- Conducting analyses of population-based studies linked to extremely large population-level datasets based on electronic health records.
- Developed skills in programming, statistical analyses, project management, using GitHub to collaborate and manage projects, data visualisation and scientific writing.

Co-Founder and Event Co-Director

Bristol Track Club

August 2018 - Ongoing

Pristol, UK

- Co-founded training group and running events brand based in Bristol (Website).
- Gained experience in: events management and coordination, people management and building a brand.

Visiting Researcher

University of Copenhagen

🛗 January 2020

- **♀** Copenhagen, Denmark
- Visiting researcher for 2 weeks undertaking analyses as part of a wider project.
- Gained experience in: having to adapt quickly to working with a new team, working in an unfamiliar environment, working to tight deadlines and presenting my work to a scientific audience.

Doctoral Candidate

Bristol Medical School, University of Bristol

September 2017 - February 2022 ♥ Bristol, UK

- Highly competitive 4-year PhD programme funded by the British Heart Foundation. Learned to effectively manage projects and tasks on my own as well as forming several collaborations internally and internationally.
- Received formal training in: Epidemiology, Statistics, Coding (R, Linux and command line tools) and gained experience in: working with and quickly adapting to different teams, project management, presenting/public speaking.

Freelance Medical Writer

Aspire Scientific

August 2019 - December 2020

Remote

• As a freelance medical writer, I helped produce a diverse range of high-quality scientific materials. This role often had strict deadlines and required me to work on topics I had no prior knowledge of.

SUMMARY

Highly motivated Epidemiologist / Health Data Scientist with 5+ years of experience working with large complex datasets. Strives to maintain key working philosophies of quality, efficiency and consistency. Experienced in coding (particularly using R for statistical analyses and data visualisation), project management, public speaking and writing for a wide range of audiences.

EDUCATION

PhD, Epidemiology

University of Bristol, Bristol, UK

BSc, Sport & Exercise Science - First University of Surrey, Guildford, UK

SKILLS

- General: Statistics, Programming, Data Viz, Project Management, Public Speaking, Writing (scientific and lay), Student Supervision, Collaboration
- Programming / Software (Proficient): R, GitHub, Microsoft Office, Linux & Command Line Tools
- **Programming / Software (Familiar):** SQL, Stata, Python, LaTeX, Shell Scripting

ACADEMIC PUBLICATIONS

For a list of my academic publications please see my Academic CV or check out my Google Scholar Profile.

AWARDS

• University of Bristol Open Research Prize for Increasing Research Quality (2021)